Git Installation Guide for macOS

1. Open the Terminal application.
2. Check if Git is already installed by running `git --version`.
3. If Git is not installed, you will be prompted to install Xcode Command Line Tools.
4. Click "Install" in the pop-up and follow the prompts.
5. Wait for the installation to complete.
6. Verify the installation by running `git --version` again.
7. Optionally, configure your name and email with:
   - `git config --global user.name "Your Name"`
   - `git config --global user.email "your.email@example.com"`.